Various Countries Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Various Countries Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 64
Yale University Arts Library
0.83
2 boxes
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of paintings by artists from various countries. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of paintings by artists from various countries. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged alphabetically by country or region. Further arranged alphabetically by artist name. The countries include Canada, the Caribbean, Czechoslovakia, Denmark, Finland, Lithuania, Luxembourg, and New Zealand.
Painting; Photographs; Reproductions
- Canada (Box 1)
  General
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings. (40 photographs)
  - Miscellaneous artists A-Z [24 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Bobak, Bruno, 1923- [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Bush, Jack, 1909-1977 [3 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Carr, Emily, 1871-1945 [3 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Casson, Alfred Joseph, 20th century [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Colville, Alex, 1920- [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Davies, Thomas, 18th century [2 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Gingras, Micheline, 1947- [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Kane, Paul, 1810-1871 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Krieghoff, Cornelius, 1812-1872 [2 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Lismer, Arthur, 1885-1969 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - MacDonald, J.E.H., 1873-1932 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Menses, Jan. 20th century [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Morrice, J.W., 1865-1923 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Newton, Lilias Torrance, 1896-1980 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - O'Brien, Lucius R., 1832-1890 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Reindorf, Samuel, 20th century [2 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Thomson, Tom, 1877-1917 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
  - Individual artists [16 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Gagnon, Clarence [5 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Harris, Lawren [3 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings (Box 1)
    - Riopelle, Jean Paul [8 photographs] (Box 1)
- Caribbean (Box 1)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings. [24 photographs]
  - Cuba [26 photographs] (Box 1)
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings
    - Miscellaneous artists [12 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Abela [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Bermudez, Cundo [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Carreno, Mario [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Diago, Roberto [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Enriquez, Carlos [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Garcia, Victor Manuel, 1897-1969 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Mariano [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Pelaez, Amelia [4 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Ponce [1 photograph] (Box 1)
    - Individual artists [14 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Lam, Wilfredo [14 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Haiti [8 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous artists [8 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Auguste, Philippe [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Benoit, Rigaud [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Bien-Aime, Charlemagne [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Duffaut, Prefette [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Hyppolite, Hector, 1894-1948 [2 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Obin, Antoine [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Obin, Philome [1 photograpgh] (Box 1)
  - Puerto Rico [3 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous artists [3 photographs] (Box 1)
      - Campeche, José, 1760-1814 [1 photograph] (Box 1)
      - Fernandez, Agustin [2 photographs] (Box 1)
- Czechoslovakia (Box 2)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings. [23 photographs]
  - Miscellaneous artists [11 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Artist unknown [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Master of the Trebon Altar [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Master of the Vyssi Brod Cycle [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Master of Saint George Altarpiece [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Vacslav Brozik, 1851-1901 [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Brocik, V. [1 photograph[ (Box 2)
    - Cerný, V.J. [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Kubista, Bohumil [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Spala, Vaclav [1 photograph] (Box 2)
  - Individual artists [12 images] (Box 2)
    - Kupka, Franz [12 images] (Box 2)
- Denmark (Box 2)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings. [74 photographs]
  - Miscellaneous artists [37 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Artist unknown [2 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Artist unknown [2 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Artist unknown [2 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Abildgaard, Nicolai Abraham, 1743-1809 [2 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Als, Peter, 1725-1775 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Block, Charles Henri, 1834-1890 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Exner, John Julius [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Hammershøi, Vilhelm, 1864-1916 [2 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Jensen, Christian Albrecht, 1792-1870 [2 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Juel, Jens, 1745-1802 [3 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Lorck, Melchio, 1527-1583 (?) [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Lundbye, Johan Thomas, 1818-1848 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Lundstrøm, Vilhelm, 1893-1950 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Melbye, Anton, 1818-1875 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Roed, Jörgen, 1808-1888 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Scwarz, Frans [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Skovgaard, Peter Christian, 1817-1875 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Sonne, Jørgen, 1801-1890 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Vermehren, Johann Frederick, 1810-1850 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
      - Wentorf, Carl Christian Ferd., 1863-1914 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
    - Individual artists [37 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Carstens, Asmis Jakob, 1754-1798 [3 photographs] (Box 2)
      - Eckersberg, Christoffer-Wilhelm, 1783-1853 [8 photographs] (Box 2)
- Finland (Box 2)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Miscellaneous artists [3photographs] (Box 2)
    - Edelfelt, Albert Gustaf Aristide, 1854-1905 [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Marquet, Albert, 1875-1947 [1 photograph] (Box 2)
- Lithuania (Box 2)
- Luxembourg (Box 2)
- New Zealand (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous artists [2 photographs] (Box 2)
    - Pearson, Alan, 1929- [2 photographs] (Box 2)